TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
잡았다!
You're mine!
기능 정지. 기능 정지.
Function ceased. Function ceased.
알겠어? 데스 메다로트를 쓰러트리려면 데스 메다로트가 아니면 불가능해.
Do you understand that only Death Medarot can take down a Death Medarot?
괜찮으면 이 엑스사이즈, 네게 줄게.
If you'd like, you can have this Excise.
뭐라고!?
What!?
엑스사이즈를 네게 주는 거에는 조건이 둘 있어.
I'll need you to abide by 2 conditions if you want Excise.
첫째는 지금 파트너인 도쿠스를 버리는 거.
First is to abandon your current partner, Dorcus.
또 하나는 네 손으로 메타비를 쓰러트리는 거야.
The other is to take Metabee down with your own hands.
잇키. 내가 상대다.
Ikki. You're fighting me.
전사의 정: 후편
Compassion of Warriors: Part 2
(en: Dark Alliance: Part II)
어이! 네 적은 데스 메다로트가 아니었냐!
Hey! Wasn't your enemy Death Medarots?!
무르구나, 잇키. 로보틀은 이미 시작했다.
How naive, Ikki. The Robattle has already begun.
뭐가 로보틀이야! 2대로 공격하다니! 이런 건 로보틀이 아니야! 그냥 싸움일 뿐이지!
You call this a Robattle?! There are two on your side! This is not a Robattle; this is just a quarrel!
제기랄!
Damn!
어쩐담...
What should I do?
바리스터, 퓨저, 동시에 발사해!
Fire Ballister and Fusier at once!
덕트 슈터, 발사!
Fire Duct Shooter!
베어라, 엑스사이즈.
Cut him, Excise.
메타비!
Metabee!
비겁해! 2대 1이라니! 그런 게 어디 있어!
How cowardly of you! Two versus one? That's bullshit!
시끄러워! 졌으면 어서 꺼져!
Shut up! You lost, and now, get lost!
가자, 잇키.
Let's go, Ikki.
수수께끼의 메다로터. 네게 실망했어.
Hey, Mysterious Medarotter, I'm disappointed at you.
약속대로 엑스사이즈를 네게 주겠어.
As we promised, you can have Excise now.
뭐?! 이 놈한테 엑스사이즈를 준다고?!
What?! You're giving this guy Excise?!
마음에 안 들어...
I don't like that...
마음에 안 들면 언제든지 상대해 주지.
If you don't, then feel free to challenge me whenever you want.
뭐야?!
What?!
망할.
Damn.
말했잖니? 데스 메다로트는 신경쓰지 않는 게 좋다고.
Didn't you listen to me? I told you to ignore Death Medarots.
이렇게 될 때까지 싸우게 만들고...
You made him fight, and look at what happened to him.
메다로트는 싸움의 도구가 아니야. 알고는 있어? 이거 참...
Medarots are not for quarreling. Did you forget, or what?
잇키가...
It's not Ikki...
잇키가 잘못한 게 아니야.
It's not Ikki's fault.
메타비.
Metabee.
메다로트가 싸움의 도구가 아니라는 것 정도는 알고 있어. 오히려 그러니까 놈들을 용서하지 못하겠어!
I know that Medarots are not for quarreling. That's why I can't forgive them!
로보틀 정신을 무시하고 싸우는 데스 메다로트를 그냥 조용히 보고만 있을 수는 없었어!
I couldn't just stand watching Death Medarots fighting, ignoring the Robattle spirits!
그래, 너희가 거기까지 알고 있다면 더 이상 말하지 않을게.
All right. If you know that far, then I won't say anything more.
아리카? 그 디지털 스패너 가져다 줄래?
Arika, can you get me the digital spanner over there?
네.
Yes.
준비 됐지, 턴멍키?
Are you ready, Turnmonkey?
바스구울!
Bassghoul!
이자식! 데스 메다로트 사냥 따윌 해서 그냥 넘어갈 수 있을 거라 생각했어?
You bastard! Did you think that you can just walk along while hunting Death Medarots?!
데스 메다로트를 쓰러뜨리는 건 내 일이다.
My job is to take Death Medarots down.
웃기지 마라! 네가 쓰고 있는 것도 데스 메다로트잖아!
Don't be absurd! You are using Death Medarot, after all!
있잖아.
Hey.
모모카와도 당했어. 그런 놈한테 엑스사이즈를 준 게 잘 한 거야? 동료가 하나하나 당하고 있는데.
Momokawa is also done for. Are you sure that giving him Excise was a good idea? Our friends are getting down.
동료? 언제나 이기는 게 내 동료야.
Friends? Whoever keeps winning is my friend.
약한 놈에게 데스 메다로터의 자격은 없어.
Weak ones do not deserve to be Death Medarotters.
데스 메다로트 사냥, 난 응원하고 있어.
I am for Death Medarot hunt.
아마자케 신문: 수수께끼의 메다로터, 결국 코쿠류하고 손을 잡다!
Amazake News: Mysterious Medarotter joined forces with Kokuryu!
어이, 아리카! 왜 메타비가 쓰러진 사진이 제일 큰 거야! 보기 안 좋잖아!
Hey, Arika! Why is the picture of fallen Metabee the biggest!? It's so unsightly!
2:1로 싸우다니, 로보틀 정신에 반하는 비열한 행위는 모두에게 알릴 의무가 있어! 저널리스트로써!
Fight in 2:1 is a contemptible action of going against Robattle spirit and I am obliged to let everyone know as a journalist!
수수께끼의 메다로터, 꽤나 폼난다고 생각했더니 경멸이야!
I thought the Mysterious Medarotter was cool, but now I look down of him!
자기부터 데스 메다로트를 쓰는 주제에 뭐가 데스 메다로트 사냥이야? 그런 건 어떻게 봐도 우스워.
For using Death Medarot, it's absurd to call it Death Medarot hunt!
결국 내 적은 데스 메다로트라고 입으로만 번지르르하게 말해 놓고 하는 짓은 데스 메다로터하고 다를 게 없잖아, 그치, 유즈루?
For having told that his enemy is Death Medarots, he acts like a Death Medarotter. Don't you agree, Yuzuru?
뭐, 거 참, 정말...
Well, that is, too bad...
내가 데스 메다로터?
I'm a Death Medarotter?
어, 잇키! 저거 뭐라고 쓰여 있어? 수수께끼 메다로터에 관련된 거야?
Hey, Ikki! What's written on there? Is it about the Mysterious Medarotter?
넌 안 보는 게 나을 거야.
You don't want to know. Believe me.
어?
What?
기다렸지?
Are you ready?
어? 딱히 나 기다리던 거 아닌데?
Huh? Ready for what?
그럼 가자.
Then, let's go.
야, 간다니 어디에 가는데?
Hey, where are we going?
어디냐니, 수수께끼의 데스 메다로터를 찾으러 가는게 당연하잖아?
Isn't it obvious? We're going to find the Mysterious Death Medarotter!
수수께끼의 데스 메다로터?
Mysterious Death Medarotter?
수수께끼의 메다로터 말야. 그런 놈, 오늘부터 수수께끼의 데스 메다로터라고 부르기로 했어.
Mysterious Medarotter, if you want. I decided to call him Mysterious Death Medarotter from now on.
자, 가자.
Now, let's go.
우리도?
We too?
잇키. 너도 걔 찾아서 끝장을 보고 싶지 않아?
Ikki. Don't you want to find him and settle this?
이대로는 안 끝나잖아?
You won't get anywhere if you don't do anything!
그래, 반드시 이 원한은 갚아야지!
Right, we have a debt to pay back!
그렇지. 이번에는 1:1로 정정당당하게 로보틀로 승리다!
Right. We're having a fair and square Robattle match by 1:1!
그래, 그럼 출발!
Well then! Let's go!
여기까지 왔으니...
Now that we're here...
끝장내라.
Finish him.
엑스사이즈. 나는 데스 메다로터냐?
Excise. Am I a Death Medarotter?
명령의 의미를 이해하지 못했습니다.
Command interpretation failure.
아니, 됐다. 아무것도 아니야.
Well, forget it. It doesn't matter.
너라면 어떻게 생각해, 도쿠스?
What do you think, Dorcus?
역시 수수께끼의 데스 메다로터야. 잘 숨어 있네.
That's expected from the Mysterious Death Medarotter. He's pretty good at hiding.
그러니까, 아무 증거도 없는데 찾는 거 무리잖아?
Again, isn't it a bad idea to look for something when you have no clue whatsoever?
-어, 저거 도쿠스 아냐?
-정말이야.
-Hey, isn't that Dorcus?
-Yeah...
도쿠스라면 수수께끼의 메다로터가 어디 있는지 알고 있을 지도 몰라!
Maybe Dorcus would know where the Mysterious Medarotter is!
가 보자!
Let's go!
그 말은 수수께끼의 메다로터가 데스 메다로트를 파트너로 얻기 위해서 널 버렸단 거야?
Are you saying that the Mysterious Medarotter abandoned you to get a Death Medarot as his new partner?
-너무해.
-너 그래도 괜찮냐? 안 분해?
-How cruel!
-Are you fine with that? Aren't you mortified!
분하다니 왜입니까?
Mortified? Why would I be mortified?
왜냐니, 너는 그 마스터한테 버려졌잖아!
Why, you ask? You are abandoned by your master!
저는 마스터가 지시한 사항에 따를 뿐입니다.
I simply follow my master's orders.
뭔 소리야, 쟤.
What is he even saying?
그래도... 왠지 불쌍해.
Still... I pity him.
야! 너 갈 곳은 있냐?
Hey! Do you even have a place to go?
정말 넌 메다로트 주제에 귀찮게 하네.
You sure are making a lot of fusses for a Medarot.
시꺼.
Shaddup.
저런, 괜찮지 않니? 다시 활기차지고.
Don't you think it's great? Our house is livelier again!
네 집이라 생각하고 편하게 있어.
You can think this place as your home and relax.
내가 이겼어!
I win!
잇키, 내 어깨 안마해라.
Ikki, massage my shoulders.
잠깐! 너 방금 치트했잖아!
Wait! You cheated!
멍청한 소리 마!
Don't be stupid!
그러니까 방금 그거 이상했잖아!
That just now wasn't right!
어딜 봐서! 지가 못한 주제에 내 탓 마라!
What's not right?! It's your fault, not mine!
뭐라고?! 이 엉터리 메다로트가!
What?! You junk Medarot!
엉터리라고?! 밖으로 나와라!
Junk, you say?! See me in the yard!
그래! 바라던 바다!
Great! That's what I wanted!
-넌 맨날 내 탓만 하고 있어!
-맨날이라니, 네가 맨날맨날 잘못하니까 그렇지!
-You always blame me for everything!
-It's because you always, always make faults first!
저 둘, 언제나 저렇게 못 어울립니까?
Can those two ever get along?
그래, 싸울 정도로 사이가 좋다고 할 수 있는 거겠구나, 더 둘은.
You can say that they are doing friendly fight.
-내가 먼저였어!
-웃기지 마!
-I was first!
-You're stupid!
-나와!   -나와!
-시꺼!
-Get out!     -Get out!
-Shut up!
오늘은 혼자냐.
You're alone today?
널 여기에 부른 건 코쿠류한텐 말 안 했어.
Kokuryu doesn't know that I called you here.
그러냐.
Sure.
나는 말야, 어떻게 해도 네가 참 마음에 안 든다!
For me, I don't like you even for a smallest bit!
그래. 끝장을 내지.
Well then. Let's settle this.
결투구나.
A duel?
정말 어쩔 수 없는 둘이구나.
They really can't be helped.
가라, 유니트리스!
Go, Unitrix!
엑스사이즈, 신소드다.
Excise, use Sin Sword.
자, 오늘이야말로 데스 메다로트 사냥의 순간을 담을 거야.
Today is the day that I'll take pictures of Death Medarot hunt in action.
오늘은 작전을 바꾸어 수수께끼의 데스 메다로터가 분명 나타날 만 한 곳에 잠복할 거야.
Today, we'll change strategy and ambush in a place where the Mysterious Death Medarotter's gonna appear.
-흥!
-Hmph!
그래도, 수수께끼의 데스 메다로터가 나타날 만한 곳이라니, 어디야?
But still, do you have any idea about those likely places that Mysterious Death Medarotter would appear?
그건...
For that...
지금부터 찾지 뭐.
We're gonna find that out.
-흥!
-Hmph!
잠깐, 니들! 언제까지 싸울 거야?
Hey, you guys! That's enough!
이 엉터리 메다로트가 사과할 때까지!
Until this junk Medarot apologizes!
뭐야?! 엉터리라고?!
What?! Junk!?
싸울래?!
Wanna fight?
자.
Here.
나하고 브라스는 저쪽 찾을 테니까 니들도 잘 해봐.
Brass and I are going to look at that direction. You guys are on your own.
이런 곳에서 데스 메다로트 사냥을 하긴 할까?
Death Medarot hunt at a place like this?
그렇게 생각하면 딴 곳에 가면 되잖아.
If you think so, then go somewhere else!
흥, 그런 곳에 숨는 게 숨는 거냐! 온 몸이 다 보이는구만.
Hmph, you think you can hide there? I can see your whole body.
뭐?! 너야말로 텅 빈 쓰레기통이니 우리 속 원숭이 같아!
What?! You look like a monkey in cage, for being inside an empty trash can!
헤! 이 엉터리 놈!
Got you! You junk!
또 그 소리 했겠다!
That again?!
용서 못 해!
Unforgivable!
어떠냐! 이래도 우리 안 원숭이라고는 못할 테다!
How's this?! You aren't calling me a monkey in cage anymore!
봐라! 나야말로 완벽히 수풀로 위장했지!
Look! I'm perfectly disguised as a bush!
나야말로 완벽해!
I'm even more perfect!
꼴 좋다!
What a sight!
잇키, 너, 그건...
Ikki, that was wonderful!
너, 너, 쓰레기, 쓰, 쓰레기 같아!
Y- you look like a t- trash!
싸울 정도로 사이가 좋다.
Friendly fighting.
도쿠스!
Dorcus!
이런 곳에서 뭐 하고 있어?
What are you doing at a place like this?
저는...
I...
저는 마스터하고 싸운 적이 없습니다.
I never fought with my master.
그리고 지금 여러분처럼 크게 웃은 적도 없었습니다.
And I never bursted out laughing like you two.
잇키! 수수께끼의 데스 메다로터가 어디 있는지 알아냈어! 서둘러!
Ikki! I found out where the Mysterious Death Medarotter is! Hurry!
저도!
Me too!
따라가도 괜찮습니까?
...can I go with you?
거기다, 가라!
Right there! Go!
왼쪽이다. 왼쪽으로 돌아.
Left. Turn left.
여기구나!
Here it is!
수수께끼의 메다로터!
Mysterious Medarotter!
싸울 거라면 나하고 로보틀해라!
If you're gonna fight, then fight me!
시꺼! 방해하지 마!
Shut up! Don't get in our way!
가자! 메다로트 전송!
Let's do this! Transfer Medarot!
마스터. 저와 싸워 주세요.
Master. Please fight against me.
뭔 소리냐, 도쿠스. 내 적은 데스 메다로트다. 네가 아니라.
What are you saying, Dorcus? My enemy is Death Medarots. Not you.
시끄럽다. 나와 싸워라.
Silence. Fight me.
각오해라.
Prepare yourself.
도쿠스. 나와 로보틀하는 것에 무슨 의미가 있냐.
Dorcus. What's the point of Robattling against me?
마스터. 이건 로보틀이 아닙니다. 이건 싸움입니다. 저와 마스터의 싸움.
Master. This is not a Robattle. This is a fight. Fight between me and Master.
뭔 소리냐.
What are you saying?
마스터는 싸울 정도로 사이가 좋다는 말을 알고 있습니까?
Master, do you know about friendly fights?
뭐라?
What?
저는 마스터와 더 사이가 좋아지고 싶습니다.
I want to get along with you more, Master.
도쿠스.
Dorcus.
도쿠스! 어떻게든 떨어져!
Dorcus! Separate!
그런 건 어서 해치우고 나하고 싸워라! 슛 스피어!
Get rid of that immediately and fight me! Shoot Spear!
도쿠스!
Dorcus!
자, 영원히 기능 정지시켜 줄까나.
Now, it's time to make you cease functioning permanently.
놓아라, 엑스사이즈.
Release him, Excise.
텐료 잇키. 너는 도쿠스의 사용 방법을 모르는구나.
Tenryo Ikki. You do not know how to use Dorcus.
너 배신하냐!
Are you betraying us?!
메다롯치를 빌려줘 봐.
Lend me your Medarotch.
마스터.
Master.
빌리는 게 아니라, 이건 네 것이잖아?
I won't lend you this; it's yours, after all.
이걸로 싸움은 끝. 지금부터는 로보틀이다! 정정당당하게 싸워 보자!
This is the end of fighting. From now on, it's a Robattle! Let's fight fair and square!
셔터 찬스!
Shutter chance!
결국 이렇게 됐구나.
So this is how it comes to be.
안됐네. 너하고는 친구가 될 수 있을 거라고 생각했는데.
Too bad. I thought I could be friends with you.
엑스사이즈 재기동.
Excise, reboot.
메타비 전송!
Transfer Metabee!
기다리다 지칠 뻔했네!
I was getting tired of waiting!
엉터리 놈이! 해치워라, 유니트리스!
Those junks! Take them down, Unitrix!
해 보자, 도쿠스.
Let's do this, Dorcus.
예, 마스터.
Right, Master.
대단해! 정말 대단해!
Awesome! Truly awesome!
빨라!
So quick!
역시 성능 차이가 너무 큰가.
The difference in performance is too great.
잡아라!
Get them!
어디냐.
Where are you?
해라, 엑스사이즈!
Do it, Excise!
멈춰!
Stop it!
무슨 힘이야!
What a power!
아직아직!
Not yet!
배터리가 파손됐어.
The battery has been damaged.
위험해! 오지 마!
Watch out! Don't come any further!
고압 전선! 긴카이! 다가오면 안 돼! 멈춰!
High voltage power code! Ginkai! Stop right there! You can't come any further!
하! 내게 애원은 안 먹혀!
Hah! Tears don't change me!
가라, 유니트리스!
Go, Unitrix!
저런...
No way...
이제 배터리가 얼마 없다.
My battery is running low.
도쿠스, 배터리 방전까지 앞으로 30초 남았습니다.
30 seconds remaining until Dorcus' battery runs out.
죄송합니다, 마스터. 저는 이제 틀렸습니다.
I am sorry, Master. I am no good anymore.
나는 포기하지 않는다.
I do not give up.
나는 널 믿는다. 그러니까, 도쿠스, 너도 포기하면 안 된다.
I believe in you. That's why you must not give up, Dorcus.
마스터.
Master.
앞으로 7초.
7 seconds remaining.
최후까지 포기하지 마라.
Do not give up until the end.
너무 괴롭혔더니 더는 못 보겠어.
It's hard to keep looking after tormenting you so much.
부숴버려, 엑스사이즈!
Crush it, Excise!
지금이다!
Now!
설마. 계산대로는 도쿠스의 배터리는 안 남아있을 텐데.
No way. Dorcus' battery should have been depleted by now.
그게 너희 약점이다.
And that is your weakness.
메다로트에게는 계산할 수 없는 일도 일어난다.
Incalculable things happen to Medarots.
뭔 소리야?
What do you mean?
메다로트에게 있고 데스 메다로트에게 없는 것. 그것은...
What Medarot has while Death Medarot doesn't is...
정신력이다.
Willpower.
정신력으로 배터리 안 남아 있는 걸 꺾었다고?
He used willpower in place of battery?
메다로트와 메다로터의 서로를 믿는 마음이 기적을 일으킨 거구나.
Medarot and Medarotter's believing minds made a miracle.
가자, 긴카이.
Let's go, Ginkai.
유니트리스하고 엑스사이즈는?
What about Unitrix and Excise?
나중에 우라가스미한테 회수하라고 하면 되지.
I'll tell Uragasumi to take them back later.
아, 그래.
Er, okay.
마, 마스터...
M- Master...
아무 말 말고 쉬어라.
Don't say a word, and take a rest.
도쿠스 전송.
Transfer Dorcus.
왠지 끝은 좀 감동이네.
The last moment was kinda moving.
그래서 사진은 찍었어?
So, did you take pictures?
벌써 가득! 내일의 아마자케 신문은 수수께끼의 데스 메다로터, 도쿠스하고의 우정으로 정했어!
I took a lot! Tomorrow's Amazake News will feature the Mysterious Death Medarotter and Dorcus' friendship!
아니, 그 녀석은 더는 데스 메다로터가 아니야.
No, he's not a Death Medarotter anymore.
우리하고 똑같이 메다로터야.
He's a Medarotter, just like us.
수수께끼는 수수께끼지만.
Mystery remains a mystery, though.
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
폭풍치는 밤, 음양 마을에 붉은 악마가 출현.
In a stormy night, a red devil appears in Ginjou village.
마을의 동력 기계를 파괴하고, 경찰의 비상 센서까지 돌파해 버린다.
It destroyed power generators of village, and destroyed through emergency sensors of police.
적으로 간주되는 것은 철저히 부수는 궁극의 전투 데스 메다로트.
This is an ultimate battle Death Medarot which destroys everything that's considered as its enemy.
과연 잇키와 메타비는 폭주하는 붉은 악마를 멈출 수 있을 것인가?
Will Ikki and Metabee manage to stop the raging red devil?
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 폭주! 붉은 악마
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Rage! Red Devil
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!